A few days ago, image editing changed
forever. Google released Gemini Flash
2.5 image, coincidentally with the same
nickname my ex-girlfriend gave me, Nano
Banana, that has everyone buying puts on
Adobe because Photoshop is officially
dead. Instead of learning how to use all
these antique tools, you can now just
prompt Nano Banana for changes and it's
able to deliver any photo alterations
you can imagine. And most importantly,
while maintaining the consistency of the
original image. If you're an animator or
graphic designer, this can unlock
massive productivity gains. Like if you
wanted to steal some Meat Canyon art and
make it do something else, you can now
accomplish that with a single prompt. No
talent necessary. Google is finally back
to its roots building cool stuff and
Flash 2.5 is a tool that makes stable
diffusion look like Microsoft Paint. In
today's video, we'll take a look at all
of its capabilities and find out if our
Adobe puts will actually print. It is
August 29th, 2025, and you're watching
the code report. Not only is Nano Banana
an exceptional image model that's
already at the top of the LM Marina
leaderboard, but it's also extremely
fast and affordable, costing only 3.9
cents per image via the API. And
hypothetically, Google has also trained
an even more powerful grande banana, but
it's unlikely the common man will ever
get access to it. The upgrade that most
people are talking about, though, is
character consistency. If you start with
an image of a person or pet, for
example, the model can blend it with a
different image or make minor changes to
it without noticeably altering the
original character. Or multiple
characters and objects like this guy did
by blending 13 different images
together. That means if you want a
LinkedIn headsh shot of yourself wearing
a nice suit, but can't afford to buy an
actual suit, Nano Banana has you
covered. In addition, if you work for
the shadow government, it can be used to
implement Mandela effects like removing
the cornucopia from the Fruit of the
Loom logo. That's cool. But if you're a
wannabe game developer, one of the main
showstoppers is the insane amount of
time it takes to build up a collection
of good-looking assets for all your
characters and animations. Well, now if
you start with a base character, you can
prompt all the different positions
required for an animation. Or better
yet, just have Gemini generate an entire
sprite for you with all of them in a
single prompt. To keep in mind, though,
if you go this route, you'll have to
disclose any AI assets used when you
publish on Steam. And you can't lie
about it because anything generated with
Google has an invisible watermark called
synth ID. What's kind of crazy about
this model though is that it also has an
understanding of the real world. Like if
you point to a spot on Google Maps and
ask what a person would see there, it
can generate a realistic photo. Or if
you're a visual learner, you can sketch
with it step by step. Like you could use
the sketch tool to map out your AWS
infrastructure. It's also pretty decent
at handling text, so you can easily turn
your images into lame Instagram ads or
memes. But it's still not perfect. So
now let's talk about the bad stuff. As
you can see in my ad here, it has a
tendency to add extra characters to
certain words. In addition, I found that
it often didn't follow my prompt exactly
and just kind of did its own thing, or
in many cases, it just ignored the
prompt and did nothing at all. And I
think even the character consistency is
a bit overhyped. I tried it on a bunch
of different images of real humans, and
it still has that obvious AI uncanny
valley look to it. And finally, as
expected as a Google product, it's
highly censored. Trying to generate
anything that's not safe for work is not
going to happen. But the best way to get
the most out of these AI tools is to
learn how they work under the hood. And
you can do that for free with Brilliant.
the sponsor of today's video. Their how
AI works course teaches you how to build
a functioning language model from
scratch and lets you experiment with
things like feature vectors to edit
facial expressions and images. This
hands-on approach to learning helps you
master challenging concepts over time
and is proven to be six times more
effective than watching video lectures.
Try everything Brilliant has to offer
for free by visiting
brilliant.org/fireship org/fireship or
scan the QR code on screen to get 20%
off their premium annual subscription
which gives you unlimited daily access
to everything on Brilliant. This has
been the code report. Thanks for
watching and I will see you in the next